Guide to St. Lawrence Seaway Collection
Erie Canal Museum
St. Lawrence Seaway Collection
1941 - 1958
Reports, maps, news articles and pamphlets related to the St. Lawrence Seaway Power Project.
5 boxes
Gay, Howard S.
Erie Canal Museum 318 Erie Boulevard East Syracuse, NY 13202
The Collection is open for research use.
This collection originally belonged to Howard S. Gay, Civil Engineer, North Atlantic Division, who worked on the St. Lawrence Seaway project.
The St. Lawrence Seaway is a system of locks, canals, and channels extending from Montreal to Lake Erie, which was constructed during the 1950s.
Saint Lawrence Seaway (N.Y.)
Various reports, maps, news articles, and pamphlets related to the St. Lawrence Seaway and Power Project. Reports are by the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, Massena, NY. Also included are some handwritten notes by Howard Gay.
- Reports
  - Reports, 1941
    - Long Sault Canal Analysis of Design, 1941, Includes item 77.108.1 (Box 1, Folder Report-Long Sault Canal, 1941)
    - Estimate of Cost-International Rapids Section, 1941, Includes item 77.108.2 (Box 1, Folder Report--Estimate of Cost, International Rapids Section, 1941)
    - Preliminary Investigations in St. Lawrence River District, 1941, Includes item 77.108.6 (Box 1, Folder Report-Preliminary Investigations in the St. Lawrence River Districe, 1941)
    - St. Lawrence Deep Waterway International Rapids Section, 1941, Includes items 77.108.7-.8 (Box 1, Folder Report-St. Lawrence Deep Waterway International Rapids Section, 1941)
    - Seismic Exploration, 1940-1941, Includes item 77.108.9 (Box 1, Folder Report-Seismic Exploration, 1940-1941)
    - Barnhart Island Power Plant Specifications--Generators, 1941, Includes items 77.108.10 (Box 1, Folder Report-Barnhart Island Power Plant Specifications, 1941)
    - Barnhart Island Power Plant Specifications--Turbines & Governors, 1941, Includes item 77.108.11 (Box 1, Folder Report-Barnhart Island Power Plant Specifications, 1941)
    - St. Lawrence Survey, Parts I-VI, 1941, Includes items 77.108.12-.17 (Box 1, Folder Report-St. Lawrence Survey Pt. I, 1941, Folder Report-St. Lawrence Survey Pt. II, 1941, Folder Report-St. Lawrence Survey Pt. III, 1941, Folder Report-St. Lawrence Survey Pt. IV, 1941, Folder Report-St. Lawrence Survey Pt. V, 1941, Folder Report-St. Lawrence Survey Pt. VI, 1941)
  - Reports, 1942
    - Analysis of Design, 1942, Includes item 77.108.23 (Box 2, Folder Report-Analysis of Design, 1942)
    - Iroquois Dam Analysis of Design, 1942, Includes item 77.108.24 (Box 2, Folder Report-Iroquois Dam Analysis of Design, 1942)
    - Long Sault Canal Analysis of Design, 1942, Includes item 77.108.25 (Box 2, Folder Report-Long Sault Canal Analysis of Design, 1942)
    - Long Sault Dam Analysis of Design, 1942, Includes item 77.108.26 (Box 2, Folder Report-Long Sault Dam Analysis of Design, 1942)
    - Point Rockway Lock Analysis of Design, 1942, Includes item 77.108.27 (Box 2, Folder Report-Point Rockway Lock Analysis of Design, 1942)
    - Robinson Bay Lock Analysis of Design, 1942, Includes item 77.108.28 (Box 3, Folder Report-Robinson Bay Lock Analysis of Design, 1942)
    - Seaway New York Analysis of Design, 1942, Includes item 77.108.29 (Box 3, Folder Report-Seaway New York Analysis of Design, 1942)
    - Estimate of Cost, 1942, Includes item 77.108.30 (Box 3, Folder Report-Estimate of Cost, 1942)
    - Main Report, 1942, Includes item 77.108.31 (Box 3, Folder Report-Main Report, 1942)
    - Final Report, Misc. Features, 1942, Includes item 77.108.32 (Box 3, Folder Report-Final Report, Misc. Features, 1942)
    - Unit Prices for Estimates, 1942, Includes item 77.108.34 (Box 3, Folder Report-Unit Prices for Estimates, 1942)
    - Misc. Design Analysis, Contracts, Construction Schedule, 1942, Includes item 77.108.37 (Box 3, Folder Report-Misc. Design Analysis, Contracts, Construction Schedule, 1942)
    - Seaway Specifications, 1942, Includes items 77.108.38-.39 (Box 3, Folder Report-Seaway Specifications, 1942)
  - Reports, 1944
    - Revised Estimate of Cost, 1944, Includes item 77.108.21 (Box 2, Folder Report-Revised Estimate of Cost, 1944)
  - Reports, 1946
    - Addendum to Final Report, 1946, Includes item 77.108.18-.20 (Box 2, Folder Report-Addendum to Final Report, 1946)
    - Study for Improvement of Galup Rapids, 1946, Includes item 77.108.22 (Box 2, Folder Report-Study for Improvement of Galup Rapids, 1946)
  - Reports, 1947
    - Tour of Inspection of St. Lawrence River & Power Project, 1947, Includes item 77.108.41 (Box 4, Folder Report--Tour of Inspection of St. Lawrence River & Power Project, 1947)
    - Photographs & Newspaper Clippings to Accompany Tour of Inspection, 1947, Includes items 77.108.42 a-k Items b-k in photo drawer K-6 (Box 4, Folder Report--Photographs & Newspaper clippings to Accompany Tour of Inspection, 1947)
  - Reports, 1948
    - Report of 1947 Board of Engineers on Lachine Section, 1948, Includes item 77.108.40 (Box 4, Folder Report--Report of 1947 Board of Engineers on Lachine Section, 1948)
    - The St. Lawrence Seaway, 1948, Includes items 77.108.44-.45 (Box 4, Folder Report--The St. Lawrence Seaway, 1948)
  - Reports, 1949
    - Some Pertinent Questions & Answers on the St. Lawrence Seaway & Power Project, 1949, Includes items 77.108.46-.47 (Box 4, Folder Report--Some Pertinent Questions & Answers on the St. Lawrence Seaway & Power Project, 1949)
    - St. Lawrence Seaway & Power Project, 1949, Includes items 77.108.48-.49 (Box 4, Folder Report--St. Lawrence Seaway & Power Project, 1949)
    - Tour of Inpsection, 1949, Includes item 77.108.52 (Box 4, Folder Report--tour of Inpsection, 1949)
  - Reports, 1951
    - Hearings Before the Committee on Public Works, 1951, Includes item 77.108.53 (Box 4, Folder Report--Hearings Before the Committee on Public Works, 1951)
    - Chart of Staff in North Atlantic Division, 1951; Includes item 77.108.54 (Box 4, Folder Report--Chart of Staff, North Atlantic Division, 1951)
    - Extract of Tabulation from Transportation Series 5, 1951, Includes item 77.108.55 (Box 4, Folder Report--Extract of Tabulation from Transportation Series 5, 1951)
    - Hudson River Channel Design, 1951, Includes item 77.108.58 (Box 4, Folder Report--Hudson River Channel Design, 1951)
  - Reports, 1952
    - Tonnage on Canadian Waterways, 1952, Includes item 77.108.56 (Box 4, Folder Report--Tonnage on Canadian Waterways, 1952)
    - Remarks by Colonel B.B. Talley, Corps of Engineers, 1952, Includes item 77.108.57 (Box 4, Folder Report--Remarks by Colonel B.B. Talley, Corps of Engineers, 1952)
  - Reports, 1953
    - Depths to be Created in Seaports, Entrance Channels, & Berths, 1953, Includes items 77.108.62-.65 (Box 4, Folder Report--Depths to be Created in Seaports, Entrance Channels, & Berths, 1953)
  - Reports, 1954
    - St. Lawrence Power, 1954, Includes item 77.108.72 (Box 5, Folder Report--St. Lawrence Power, 1954)
    - Recreation, Housing, Highways, and Related Matters, 1954, Includes item 77.108.73 (Box 5, Folder Report--Recreation, Housing, Highways, and Related Matters, 1954)
    - Comparative Costs of Steam & Hydro Transmission, 1954, Includes items 77.108.78 a-h (Box 5, Folder Report--Comparative Costs of Steam & Hydro Transmission, 1954)
    - Channel Depths, 1954, Includes items 77.108.79-.80 (Box 5, Folder Report--Channel Depths, 1954)
  - Reports, 1955
    - Data on Proposed Maritime Commission Transport Ships, 1955, Includes item 77.108.82 (Box 5, Folder Report--Data on Proposed Maritime Commission Transport Ships, 1955)
    - Construction Progress, 1955, Includes item 77.108.83 (Box 5, Folder Report--Construction Progress, 1955)
    - Questions & Answers on the St. Lawrence Seaway, 1955, Includes item 77.108.85 (Box 5, Folder Report--Questions & Answers on the St. Lawrence Seaway, 1955)
  - Reports, No Date
    - Analysis of Design--Massena/Taylorville, Includes item 77.108.87 (Box 5, Folder Reports--Analysis of Design--Massena/Taylorville)
    - Analysis of Design--Access & Relocation Bridges, Includes item 77.108.92 (Box 5, Folder Report--Analysis of Design, Access & Relocation Bridges, no date)
    - Range of Tide, Includes item 77.108.94 (Box 5, Folder Report--Range of Tide, no date)
    - Electronic Power & Lighting System for Seaway, NY, Includes item 77.108.95 (Box 5, Folder Report--Electronic Power & Lighting System for Seaway NY, no date)
    - General Description of St. Lawrence River Project, Includes item 77.108.96 (Box 5, Folder Report--General Description of St. Lawrence River Project, no date)
    - Pamphlet--Seaway Power, Includes items 77.108.99-.100 (Box 5, Folder Pamphlet--Seaway Power)
    - Report--Power, Includes item 77.108.101 (Box 5, Folder Report--Power)
    - St. Lawrence Power Project, Includes item 77.108.102 (Box 5, Folder Report--St. Lawrence Power Project)
    - Summary of Reports from District Engineers, Includes item 77.108.103 (Box 5, Folder Report--Summary of Reports from District Engineers)
    - Vessel Data, Includes item 77.108.104 (Box 5, Folder Report--Vessel Data)
    - Reports of Howard S. Gay, Includes item 77.108.105 (Box 5, Folder Report--Reports of Howard S. Gay)
  - Reports, 1956
    - Construction Progress, 1956, Includes item 77.108.89 (Box 5, Folder Reports--Construction Progress, 1956)
- Maps
  - Maps, 1941
    - St. Lawrence Waterway International Rapids Section, General Plan, January 27, 1941; Includes item 77.108.3 (Box 1, Folder Maps, 1941)
    - The Great Lakes St. Lawrence Project, January 19, 1941; Includes item 77.108.4 (Box 1, Folder Maps, 1941)
    - St. Lawrence River Project, General Plan--Sidewalks, 1941; Includes item 77.108.5 (Box 1, Folder Maps, 1941)
  - Maps, 1942
    - Water Level Profile, 1942, Includes item 77.108.35 (Box 3, Folder Map-Water Level Profile, 1942)
    - International Rapids Section, 1942, Includes item 77.108.36 (Box 3, Folder Map-International Rapids Section, 1942)
  - Maps, 1954
    - St. Lawrence Seaway, 1954, Includes items 77.108.67-.68 (Box 5, Folder Maps--St. Lawrence Seaway, 1954)
  - Maps, 1953
    - Army Corps of Engineers, Maps of Projects, 1953; Includes item 77.108.93 (Box 5, Folder Maps--Army Corps of Engineers, Maps of Projects, 1953)
  - Maps, 1930
    - Map of Canada, 1930, Includes item 77.108.97 (Box 5, Folder Map--Canada, 1930)
- Blueprints
  - Blueprints, 1942
    - Final Report-Misc. Features Plans, 1942, Includes item 77.108.33
  - Blueprints 1948
    - St. Lawrence Project on NY Ontario Frontier as it will Appear Completed, 1948, Includes item 77.108.43 (Box Oversize box 3)
- Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1949
    - Correspondence RE Tour of Inspection, 1949, Includes items 77.108.50-.51 (Box 4, Folder Correspondence--Tour of Inpsection, 1949)
  - Correspondence, 1953
    - Correspondence RE St. Lawrence Testimony, 1953, Includes items 77.108.60-.61 (Box 4, Folder Correspondence--St. Lawrence Testimony, 1953)
  - Correspondence, 1954
    - Correspondence RE St. Lawrence Seaway, 1954, Includes items 77.108.69-.70 (Box 5, Folder Correspondence--St. Lawrence Seaway, 1954)
  - Correspondence, 1955
    - Correspondence RE Great Lakes Connecting Channels, 1955, Includes item 77.108.84 (Box 5, Folder Corrrespondence--Great Lakes Connecting Channels, 1955)
- News Articles
  - News Articles, 1951
    - Life Magazine Article, 1951, Includes item 77.108.59 (Box 4, Folder News Articles--Life Magazine, 1951)
  - News Articles, 1954
    - Misc. News Reports 1954, Includes items 77.108.66, 77.108.71 (Box 5, Folder News Articles--St. Lawrence Seaway & Power Project, 1954, Folder News Articles--Progress News, 1954)
  - News Articles, 1955
    - News Articles, St. Lawrence Power Project, 1955, Includes item 77.108.81 (Box 5, Folder News Articles, St. Lawrence Power Project, 1955)
    - News Articles--Boats, 1955, 77.108.98 (Box 5, Folder News Articles--Boats, 1955)
  - News Articles, 1956
    - News Articles, St. Lawrence Seaway, 1956, Includes item 77.108.88 (Box 5, Folder News Articles--St. Lawrence Seaway, 1956)
  - News Articles, 1957
    - News Articles, St. Lawrence Seaway, 1957, Includes item 77.108.90 (Box 5, Folder News Articles--St. Lawrence Seaway, 1957)
  - News Articles, 1958
    - News Articles, St. Lawrence Seaway, 1958, Includes item 77.108.91 (Box 5, Folder News Articles--St. Lawrence Seaway, 1958)
- Press Releases
  - Press Releases, 1954
    - St. Lawrence Development, 1954, Includes items 77.108.74-.77 (Box 5, Folder Press Releases--St. Lawrence Development, 1954)
  - Press Releases, 1955
    - Progress Report and Economic Outlook, 1955, Includes item 77.108.86 (Box 5, Folder Press Release--Progress Report and Economic Outlook, 1955)